# Vishwas Navada B

137, Blessen's Nest, Manipal County Road, Singasandra, Bengaluru, India

□ vishwasnavada@gmail.com
○ vishwasnavada.github.io

Hardware design engineer with 5.5 years of work experience in hardware design and development. Currently, my work involves board design and hardware design for high-speed network switches for 5G infrastructure. Apart from work, I'm an amateur radio enthusiast and an electronics hobbyist.

## **Work Experience**

#### Tejas Networks India Pvt. Ltd.

Electronics city, Bengaluru

April 2019-Present

Senior Hardware Design Engineer

3.5 years of strong exposure in high-speed board design.

Worked on different aspects of design during the complete life-cycle of products including schematics, SI, PCB Stack-up, Layout CAD, BOM/Life-cycle management, Board bring-up, functional testing, DVT measurements and validation amongst others.

Implemented several FPGA based designs including Verilog coding and STA analysis.

Tackled several critical field issues for major customer deployments with fast workarounds/fixes.

## Robert Bosch Centre for Cyber-Physical Systems

IISc, Bengaluru

Hardware Design Engineer

April 2018-March 2019

Built an Ultra Wide Band (UWB) beacon system for Autonomous Navigation of Drones. Developed an autonomous charging pad for quadcopters and hexacopters. Designed a system for Actuation and control of Shape Memory Alloy based soft grippers.

Openwater.in Pvt. Ltd.

IISc, Bengaluru

Hardware Design Engineer

July 2017-April 2018

Worked on the design and development of Electronic systems for water filtration unit Designed customized power supply to drive the whole water purification system Designed and tested wireless water flow meters

Instrumentation and Applied Physics Department, IISc

Bengaluru

Project Assistant

March 2017-May 2017

Developed smart IoT based water quality sensors and flow meters

#### **Education**

## Academic Qualifications....

Bangalore Institute of Technology, VTU

Bengaluru

B.E Electronics and Instrumentation Engineering , Aggregate:71%, CGPA:7.85

*2013–2017* **Kota, Udupi** 

Viveka Pre-University College XII, PCME, Aggregate:89.50%

2011-2013

Government P U College

Koteshwara

X, Aggregate:90.88%

2011

## **Notable Projects**

Design and development for CPE-64 'An Enterprise switch'

This is an enterprise switch with 32G/64G/120G switching capacity, My responsibilities included: Complete Schematics Design, Board Design and cross-platform functional analysis. Verilog coding for FPGAs

• Design and development for IO-U3: 'An I/O Card for TJ1600I platform'

This card acts as an OTN Processor which can handle multiple 400Gbps optical inputs from devices like CFP2, QSFP-DD etc.

My responsibilities included: Complete Schematics Design, Board Design and cross-platform functional analysis.

Verilog coding for FPGAs

• Design and development for S-SF1: 'Fabric Card for TJ1600S platform'

This card performs cell-based switching and is used as a Fabric Element for TJ1600S Spine Chassis, provides 53G SerDes interconnect (up to 9.6Tbps) to Leaf based subsystems.

Complete Schematics Design and cross-platform functional analysis.

Deciding PCB stack up, BoM management, SI and PI analysis, and assisting Layout team to meet all Hardware and manufacturing recommendations.

Verilog coding for CFPGA (Altera Cyclone V) and STA analysis for all necessary interfaces.

Complete bring up and testing of the card including traffic testing of 56G PAM4 links.

Design and development for the S-PSC: 'Power Supply Controller for TJ1600S platform'

This card controls multiple power supplies based on a custom algorithm and load requirements. Complete Schematics Design and cross-platform functional analysis.

Deciding PCB stack up, BoM management, SI and PI analysis, and assisting Layout team to meet all Hardware and manufacturing recommendations.

Verilog coding for CFPGA (Altera Cyclone V) and STA analysis for all necessary interfaces. Complete bring up and testing of the card.

• Autonomous Drone Charging Pad 'A smart charger atop street lights'

Autonomous drone charging pad that uses UWB precision localisation and smart charging technology to charge drones

My responsibilities included: Complete Schematics Design, Board Design and embedded systems for the navigation and charging systems

## **Under Graduate/Hobby Projects**

- Smart Beehive monitoring systems (06/2021-Present) 'Bee health monitoring using audio analysis and TinyML'
- Touch-free retrofit switches for COVID-19 (7/2020-Present) 'Retrofit module fits on the existing switchboard to turn on and turn off the switches'
- o Raksha (04/2020 06/2020) 'Vitals monitoring wearable for early detection of COVID-19'
- o Azure smart energy meter with IoT Locker (10/2019 11/2019) 'Azure cloud-based smart energy meter that monitors the power consumption and works as a smart locker'
- Vega Drone Health Monitoring Systems (04/2019 06/2019) 'Predictive maintenance for drones using AI and pattern recognition of vibrations'
- Smart Soft Switch (11/2018 12/2018) 'Infineon MOSFET SoftSwitch for Spark Free connection in Drones'
- Simultaneous Localisation And Mapping (SLAM) using drones (01/2017-05/2017) 'Simultaneous Localisation and Mapping using a quadcopter and a Kinect Camera'

### **Technical and Personal skills**

- o Programming Languages: Proficient in C, Python, MatLab, Arduino, TeX, Verilog and bash scripting.
- o Industry Software Skills: DxDesigner, Expedition, Allegro, KiCad, Eagle, Sigrity Power SI, Sigrity, SIWave, PCIe, DDR, PCB, Oscilloscope, Mentor, Cadence, FreeCAD, Matlab, Proteus, Eclipse, MS Office
- Protocols and Technologies: I2C, SPI, SATA, SGMII, DDR3, DDR4, PmBUS, PCIe, SD, eMMC, USB, XAUI and other high-speed protocols
- o General Business Skills: Public Speaking Skills, Good presentation skills, Works well in a team.
- Other: Good soldering and rapid prototyping skills, Can write well organised and structured reports(Written many write-ups, blogs on electronics).

### **Academic Distinctions and Publications**

- o Tata Crucible Hackathon 2021: Won 1st prize for the logistics solution using IoT Hardware
- Hardware Hackathons (04/2015-Present):
  - Most practical use of AI@Brainium,
  - Best healthcare application@ONSemi Hackathon,
  - 1st @ Reimagine Waste, IISc,
  - 1st @ Infineon hackathon,
  - 1st @ ABB Makeathon,
  - 1st @ CeBIT IoT Hackathon,
  - 3rd @ MediaTekGlobal IoT challenge,
  - Best Geek Group @ Mercedes Benz Hack.Bangalore
- o Robo Racing:1st @ Pravega, IISc, Aathmatrisha, PESU NMIT College fests
- Quizzing: 2nd @ BrainBox Quizzing, 2nd @TCS Tech Bytes, 1st@ Wright Brothers, Semi-finalist International Ericsson Awards
- o Talks: Delivered talks on
  - Applications of Edge AI(03/2022)
  - Bridging the gap between industry and academia (02/2021)
  - Why attending hackathons is important (02/2020)
  - Opensource Electronics (07/2019)
  - LoRa Communication Protocol (06/2018)

#### Opening of the property of

- Agrosquad An IoT based precision agriculture using UAV and low-power soil multi-sensor
- Robust and Scalable Techniques for TWR and TDoA based localization using Ultra Wide Band Radios
- Human-machine interaction systems encounter convergence
- LoRa Communication Protocol

## Interests and extra-curricular activity

- Actively involved and organised Robo racing competition in college fest during 2016, Conducted Free workshops on balsa wood gliders and open-source electronics to students
- o Open-source electronics contributor: I regularly write articles and blogs on Hackster.io and Element14
- o I am an amateur radio operator with call sign VU3TEY, I build various antennas and explore the hobby
- I am also an avid cyclist, having completed many long-distance rides. Other interests include watercolour painting and sketching